<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Bitcoin Miner</string>
    <string name="crypto_live_price">Bitcoin Live Price</string>
    <string name="crypto">BITCOIN</string>
    <string name="cryto_fundmentals">Bitcoin Fundamentals</string>
    <string name="cryto_trivia">Virtualcurrency Trivia Facts</string>
    <string name="cryto_guide">Understanding Bitcoin Guide</string>
    <string name="type_of_crypto">Types of Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="crypto_live_prices">Bitcoin Live Price</string>
    <string name="mine_crypto_currency">Mine Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="crypto_fundamentals">Bitcoin  Fundamentals</string>
    <string name="bitcoin_brief_history">Bitcoin Brief History</string>
    <string name="how_does_crypto_work">How does Virtualcurrency work</string>
    <string name="get_crypto">How to get Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="storing">Storing and Transations of \n Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="owning">Owning and Trading Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="benefits">5 Major benefits of Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="key">Final Thoughs and key \nTakeaways</string>
    <string name="facts">Virtualcurrency Trivia Facts</string>
    <string name="bitcoin">Bitcoin</string>
    <string name="ethereum">Ethereum</string>
    <string name="cardano">Cardano</string>
    <string name="stellar">Stellar</string>
    <string name="dogecoin">Dogecoin</string>
    <string name="tether">Tether</string>
    <string name="used_coin">USD Coin</string>
    <string name="xrp">XRP</string>
    <string name="terra">Terra</string>
    <string name="solana">Solana</string>
    <string name="alternative">Whats the alternative</string>
    <string name="all_power">Is all PoW mining the same</string>
    <string name="pow">Are there disadvantages to the PoW model</string>
    <string name="mining_work">How Virtualcurrency Mining Work</string>
    <string name="what_is_crypto_mining">What is Virtualcurrency Mining</string>
    <string name="cardona">Cardona</string>
    <string name="mine_crypto">Mine VirtualCurrency</string>
    <string name="avalanche">Avalanche</string>
    <string name="topic1">TOPIC \n 1</string>
    <string name="topic2">TOPIC \n 2</string>
    <string name="topic3">TOPIC \n 3</string>
    <string name="topic4">TOPIC \n 4</string>
    <string name="topic5">TOPIC \n 5</string>
    <string name="topic6">TOPIC \n 6</string>
    <string name="topic7">TOPIC \n 7</string>
    <string name="topic8">TOPIC \n 8</string>
    <string name="topic9">TOPIC \n 9</string>
    <string name="topic10">TOPIC \n 10</string>
    <string name="topic11">TOPIC \n 11</string>
    <string name="topic12">TOPIC \n 12</string>
    <string name="history">History of Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="who_invented">Who invented Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="rise">Rise of Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="advantages">Advantages of Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="disadvantages">Disadvantages of Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="valueratio">Virtualcurrency Valuation</string>
    <string name="anonimity">Transactions anonymity</string>
    <string name="potential">Potential of Blockchain</string>
    <string name="transaction">Transactions on Blockchain</string>
    <string name="public_or_private1">Are Blockchain Public or Private</string>
    <string name="public_or_private">Are Blockchain Public or \n Private</string>
    <string name="blockchain">Blockchain Ptential Upside</string>
    <string name="why_crypto_invent">Why were Bitcoincurrencies \n invented</string>
    <string name="invented">Who invented \n Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="what_are_crypto">What are Bitcoincurrencies</string>
    <string name="work">How does Virtualcurrency \n work</string>
    <string name="benefits_of_work">5 Major benefits of \n Virtualcurrency</string>
    <string name="avalancheSen">Avalanche (AVAX) is a virtualcurrency and blockchain platform that rivals Ethereum. AVAX is the native token of the Avalanche blockchain, which—like Ethereum—uses smart contracts to support a variety of blockchain projects.1
\nThe Avalanche blockchain can provide near-instant transaction finality. AVAX is used to pay transaction processing fees and secure the Avalanche network, and acts as a basic unit of account among blockchains in the Avalanche network.
</string>
    <string name="solanaSen">Solana is a blockchain platform designed to host decentralized, scalable applications. Founded in 2017, Solana is an open-source project currently run by Solana Foundation based in Geneva, while the blockchain was built by San Francisco-based Solana Labs.1 Solana is much faster in terms of the number of transactions it can process and has significantly lower transaction fees compared to rival blockchains like Ethereum.
\nThe virtualcurrency that runs on the Solana blockchain—also named Solana (SOLUSD) and with the ticker symbol SOL—has soared almost 12,000% so far in 2021,2 and with a market capitalization of over $66 billion, it is the fifth-largest virtualcurrency by this measure.
</string>
    <string name="terraSen">Terra is an open-source blockchain payment platform for an algorithmic stablecoin, which are virtualcurrencies that automatically track the price of currencies or other assets. The Terra blockchain enables users to instantly spend, save, trade, or exchange Terra stablecoins.
\nThe Terra protocol creates stablecoins designed to consistently track the price of a fiat currency (a government-backed currency such as the U.S. dollar or euro). It consists of two virtualcurrency tokens—Terra and Luna.
</string>
    <string name="xrpSen">Ripple is a technology that acts as both a virtualcurrency and a digital payment network for financial transactions. It was first released in 2012 and was co-founded by Chris Larsen and Jed McCaleb. Ripple main process is a payment settlement asset exchange and remittance system, similar to the SWIFT system for international money and security transfers, which is used by banks and financial middlemen dealing across currencies.
\nThe token used for the virtualcurrency is premined and utilizes the ticker symbol XRP. Ripple is the name of the company and the network, and XRP is the virtualcurrency token. The purpose of XRP is to serve as an intermediate mechanism of exchange between two currencies or networks—as a sort of temporary settlement layer denomination.
</string>
    <string name="USDSen">USD Coin (USDC) is a digital currency that is fully backed by U.S. dollar assets. USDC is a tokenized U.S. dollar, with the value of one USDC coin pegged 1:1 to the value of one U.S. dollar. The value of USDC is designed to remain stable, making USDC a stablecoin.Stablecoins are commonly backed by reserve assets like dollars or euros to achieve price stability.1 The price stability of USDC contrasts sharply with the notorious price fluctuations of other virtualcurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum.</string>
    <string name="TetherSen">Tether (USDT) is a virtualcurrency stablecoin pegged to the U.S. dollar and backed "100% by Tethers reserves," according its website.1 Tether is owned by iFinex, the Hong Kong-registered company that also owns the virtual exchange BitFinex.
\nTether was launched as RealCoin in July 2014 and was rebranded as Tether in November 2014. It started trading in February 2015.23 Originally based on the Bitcoin blockchain, Tether now supports Bitcoin Omni and Liquid protocols as well as the Ethereum, TRON, EOS, Algorand, Solana, OMG Network, and Bitcoin Cash (SLP) blockchains.
\nAs of May 2022, Tether was the third-largest virtualcurrency after 	(BTC) and Ethereum (ETH), and the largest stablecoin with a market capitalization of nearly $83 billion.5 In April 2022, Tethers USDT accounted for two-thirds of exchanges out of Bitcoin by value.
</string>
    <string name="DogecoinSen">Dogecoin is a virtualcurrency created by software engineers Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer, who decided to create a payment system as a "joke", making fun of the wild speculation in virtualcurrencies at the time.[3] It is considered both the first "meme coin", and, more specifically, the first "dog coin". Despite its satirical nature, some consider it a legitimate investment prospect. Dogecoin features the face of the Shiba Inu dog from the "doge" meme as its logo and namesake.[4][5][6] It was introduced on December 6, 2013, and quickly developed its own online community, reaching a market capitalization of over $85 billion[a] on May 5, 2021.[7] It is the current shirt sponsor (sleeve only) of Premier League club Watford.[8] Dogecoin.com promotes the currency as the "fun and friendly Internet currency", referencing its origins as a "joke."[9] Software engineers Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer launched the satirical virtualcurrency as a way to make fun of Bitcoin and the many other virtualcurrencies boasting grand plans to take over the world. With the help of Reddit, the site became an instant hit. Within two weeks, Dogecoin had established a dedicated blog and forum, and its market value has reached $8 million, once jumping to become the seventh largest electronic currency in the world.[10] Dogecoin is based on Scrypt algorithm, and the transaction process is more convenient than Bitcoin. Dogecoin takes only 1 minute to confirm, while BTC takes 10 minutes.</string>
    <string name="StellarSen">The term Stellar virtualcurrency refers to a digital or virtual currency developed by Stellar Development Foundation. The organizations currency, which is called the lumen, is traded under the symbol XLM on various virtualcurrency exchanges.1\n
        Lumens can be used by traders on the Stellar network, which is a blockchain-based distributed ledger network that connects banks, payments systems, and people to facilitate low-cost, cross-asset transfers of value, including payments.
</string>
    <string name="CardanoSen">Cardano is a third-generation, decentralized proof-of-stake (PoS) blockchain platform designed to be a more efficient alternative to proof-of-work (PoW) networks. Scalability, interoperability, and sustainability on PoW networks like Ethereum are limited by the infrastructure burden of growing costs, energy use, and slow transaction times.
\nCharles Hoskinson, the co-founder of the proof-of-work (PoW) blockchain Ethereum, understood the implications of these challenges to blockchain networks, and began developing Cardano and its primary virtualcurrency, ada, in 2015, launching the platform and the ada token in 2017.1
\nThe Cardano platform runs on the Ouroboros consensus protocol. Ouroboros, created by Cardano in its foundation phase, is the first PoS protocol that not only was proved to be secure, but also was the first to be informed by scholarly academic research. Each development phase, or era, in the Cardano roadmap is anchored by the research-based framework, incorporating peer-reviewed insights with evidence-based methods to make progress toward and achieve the milestones related to the future directions of the use applications of both the blockchain network and the ada token.21
\nAs of June 20, 2021, 71.59% of Cardanos virtualcurrency ASA, is staked in 2,626 active pools with a value of approximately $31.4 billion.

</string>
    <string name="etherumSen">Ethereum is a global virtual machine powered by blockchain technology. It is most commonly known for its native virtualcurrency, ether, or ETH. Ethereum network participants use ETH to pay for work done on the blockchain.
\nEthereum is designed to be scalable, programmable, secure, and decentralized. It is the blockchain of choice for developers and enterprises, who are creating technology based upon it to change the way many industries operate and the way we go about our daily lives.
</string>
    <string name="bitcoinSen">Bitcoin is a virtualcurrency, a virtual currency designed to act as money and a form of payment outside the control of any one person, group, or entity, and thus removing the need for third-party involvement in financial transactions. It is rewarded to blockchain miners for the work done to verify transactions and can be purchased on several exchanges.
\nBitcoin was introduced to the public in 2009 by an anonymous developer or group of developers using the name Satoshi Nakamoto.
\nIt has since become the most well-known virtualcurrency in the world. Its popularity has inspired the development of many other virtualcurrencies. These competitors either attempt to replace it as a payment system or are used as utility or security tokens in other blockchains and emerging financial technologies.
</string>
    <string name="str25">Proof of Work (PoW) protocol for virtualcurrency uses an excessive amount of electricity to secure the network. Many PoW coins do not have sufficient hashing power to secure itself. There are many alternatives to PoW, such as Proof of Stake (PoS), merge-mining etcetera, which uses much less electricity. However, these alternatives have some drawbacks either in terms of security, complexity, and scalability. In this paper, an alternative to Proof of Work (PoW) called “Proof of BID” (PoB) protocol introduced. PoB makes use of existing bitcoin PoW to secure all transactions, thus consuming virtually no electricity. PoB also addresses most of the drawbacks faced by PoW alternatives. We have disclosed a systematic method on how to effectively re-used bitcoin PoW to secure a blockchain with the same level of bitcoin security. A few designs issue to improve the blockchain scalability is given. We have explored various attack scenarios and suggested some remedies.</string>
    <string name="str24">This explanation will focus on proof of work as it functions in the bitcoin network. Bitcoin is a digital currency that is underpinned by a kind of distributed ledger known as a blockchain. This ledger contains a record of all bitcoin transactions, arranged in sequential blocks, so that no user is allowed to spend any of their holdings twice. In order to prevent tampering, the ledger is public, or distributed; an altered version would quickly be rejected by other users.4
\n\nThe way that users detect tampering in practice is through hashes, long strings of numbers that serve as proof of work. Put a given set of data through a hash function (bitcoin uses SHA-256), and it will only ever generate one hash. Due to the "avalanche effect, however, even a tiny change to any portion of the original data will result in a totally unrecognizable hash. Whatever the size of the original data set, the hash generated by a given function will be the same length. The hash is a one-way function: it cannot be used to obtain the original data, only to check that the data that generated the hash matches the original data.
</string>
    <string name="str23"><b>Point 1:- </b>The biggest disadvantage of proof-of-work centers on the computational capabilities needed to solve mathematical problems in authenticating blockchain transactions. Note that this is also one of the biggest drawbacks of blockchain, a major criticism of virtualcurrencies, and the primary reason that PoW-based blockchains have negative environmental impacts.
\n\n<b>Point 2:-</b> Of course, to participate in a blockchain network that utilizes PoW as a consensus mechanism, a party must have a powerful computer equipped with advanced hardware. Scaling the operation means purchasing and setting up more expensive computers.
\n\n<b>Point 3:-</b> But the cost does not rest alone in the aforesaid purchases. Powerful computers inherently consume a lot of energy. Furthermore, these machines require effective heat management or cooling system to remain operational and prevent overheating, as well as associated damages to hardware components due to internal heat build-up.
\n\n<b>Point 4:- </b>The same energy-intensiveness is also the reason behind the more specific disadvantages of proof-of-work. For example, because of the cost associated with running and maintaining powerful computer systems, PoW-based blockchains have scalability limitations.
\n\n<b>Point 5:- </b>In addition, the associated cost also prevents a number of individuals and organizations from participating in a particular blockchain network. Hence, while blockchain technology is based on the concept of decentralization through public participation, cost serves as a key barrier for the greater public to participate, thus creating some semblance of centralization.
</string>
    <string name="str22">Mining virtualcurrencies requires computers with special software specifically designed to solve complicated, virtualgraphic mathematic equations. In the technology early days, virtualcurrencies like Bitcoin could be mined with a simple CPU chip on a home computer. Over the years, however, CPU chips have become impractical for mining most virtualcurrencies due to the increasing difficulty levels.
\n\nToday, mining virtualcurrencies requires a specialized GPU or an application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC) miner. In addition, the GPUs in the mining rig must be connected to a reliable internet connection at all times. Each virtual miner is also required to be a member of an online virtual mining pool as well.
\n\nDetermining whether virtual mining is worthwhile depends on several factors. Whether a prospective miner chooses a CPU, GPU, ASIC miner, or cloud mining, the most important factors to consider are the mining rig’s hash rate, electric power consumption, and overall costs. Generally, virtual mining machines consume a considerable amount of electricity and emit significant heat.
\n\nFor instance, the average ASIC miner will use about 72 terawatts of power to create a bitcoin in about ten minutes. These figures continue to change as technology advances and mining difficulty increases.


</string>
    <string name="str21">(CRYPTOcurrency mining) The competitive process that verifies and adds new transactions to the blockchain for a virtualcurrency that uses the proof-of-work (PoW) method. The miner that wins the competition is rewarded with some amount of the currency and/or transaction fees. Following are the ways mining is performed. See proof-of-work algorithm.
\n\n<b>1. Individual Miners</b>
\nAnyone can purchase specialized miner hardware and connect to the Internet. This was more feasible in the early 2010s than it is today. However, new currencies come online all the time, and if they employ the proof-of-work (PoW) method rather than proof-of-stake (PoS), regular computers or computers with high-end GPUs may be sufficient for mining. See miner hardware and GPU.
\n\n<b>2. Mining Pools</b>
\nOrganizations combine their resources to obtain a huge amount of mining hardware. Mining pools are also open to the public, whereby anyone can add their computers to the network. See pool mining.
        \n\n<b>3. Cloud Mining</b>
\nPeople can rent time on a cloud mining service and pay a monthly fee. See cloud mining.
\n\n<b>4. Mining Energy</b>
\nThe puzzle that miners attempt to solve for Bitcoin and Ethereum, the two major cryptos, consumes a lot of electricity. Known as the "proof-of-work" consensus algorithm, the Digiconomist website (www.digiconomist.net) says Bitcoin and Ethereum together consume as much energy as Indonesia. However, Ethereum is changing its consensus method, which began in late 2020 (see Ethereum 2.0). Contrast with virtual minting. See consensus mechanism, virtual mining malware, blockchain, Bitcoin mining and virtualjacking.


</string>
    <string name="str20">Now as virtual transforms into an increasingly mainstream industry, even the ostensibly legitimate actors — start-up founders, engineers and investors — insist on anonymity. A growing number of virtual entrepreneurs, many of whom control hundreds of millions of dollars in investor funds, conduct business via mysterious internet avatars scrubbed of identifying information. Some venture capital firms are backing founders without ever learning their real names.\n\nBut the near collapse of Wonderland is forcing a reckoning over whether this culture of anonymity undermines accountability and enables fraud. Last month, BuzzFeed News set off a fresh round of debate by identifying two of the pseudonymous founders of Bored Ape Yacht Club, a $2.5 billion collection of nonfungible tokens, the unique digital collectibles known as NFTs.</string>
    <string name="str19"><b>1. Illegal transactions:</b>
\nSince the privacy and security of virtualcurrency transactions are high, it’s hard for the government to trace down any user by their wallet address or keep tabs on their data. Bitcoin has been used as a mode of payment (exchanging money) during many illegal deals in the past, like buying drugs on the dark web. It has also been used by some people to convert their illicitly acquired money to hide its source, through a clean intermediary.
\n\n<b>2. Risk of Data Loss:</b>
\nThe developers wanted to make virtually untraceable ASCII documents, strong hacking defenses, and impenetrable authentication protocols. It would make it safer to position money in virtualcurrencies than physical cash or bank vaults. But if any user loses the private key to their wallet, there is no getting it back. The wallet will remain locked away along with the number of coins inside it. It might result in the loss of the user.
\n\n<b>3. Power lies in few hands:</b>
\nAlthough virtualcurrencies are known for their feature of being decentralized, the flow and amount of some currencies within the market are still controlled by their creators and some organizations. These holders can manipulate the coin for enormous swings in its price. Even hugely traded coins are at risk of these manipulations like Bitcoin, whose value doubled several times in 2017.
\n\n<b>4. Buying NFTs with other tokens:</b>
\nSome virtualcurrencies can only be traded in one or some fiat currencies. It forces the user to convert these currencies into one all told the most currencies, like Bitcoin or Ethereum first and then through other exchanges, to their desired currency. It can apply to just some virtualcurrencies. By doing this, the extra transaction fees are added within the method, costing unnecessary money.
5. No refund or cancellation:
If there is a dispute between concerned parties, or if someone mistakenly sends funds to a wrong wallet address, the coin cannot be retrieved by the sender. It might be utilized by many folks to cheat others out of their money. Since there are no refunds, one can easily be created for a transaction whose product or services they never received.
6. High consumption of Energy:
Mining virtualcurrencies require plenty of computational power and electricity input, making it highly energy-intensive. The main culprit during this is often Bitcoin. Mining Bitcoin requires advanced computers and plenty of energy. One cannot do it on ordinary computers. Major Bitcoin miners are in countries like China that use coal to produce electricity. It has increased China’s carbon footprint tremendously.
7. Vulnerable to hacks:
Although virtualcurrencies are very secure, exchanges don’t seem to be that secure. Most exchanges store the wallet data of users to figure their user ID correctly. This data is often stolen by hackers, giving them access to lots of accounts.
After getting access, these hackers can efficiently transfer funds from those accounts. Some exchanges, like Bitfinex or Mt Gox, have been hacked within the past years, and Bitcoin has been stolen in thousands and countless US dollars. Most exchanges are highly secure nowadays, but there is always a possibility for a further hack.
</string>
    <string name="str18"><b>1. Protection from inflation:</b>
\nInflation has caused many currencies to urge their value to decline with time. At the time of its launch, almost every virtualcurrency is released with a tough and fast amount. The ASCII computer file specifies the quantity of any coin; there are only 21 million Bitcoins released within the planet. So, because the demand increases, its value will increase which might maintain with the market and, within the long run, prevent inflation.
\n\n<b>2. Self-governed and managed:</b>
\nGovernance and maintenance of any currency is also a serious factor for its development. The virtualcurrency transactions are stored by developers/miners on their hardware, which they get the transaction fee as a gift for doing so. Since the miners have become acquired it, they keep transaction records accurate and up-to-date, keeping the integrity of the virtualcurrency and also the records decentralized.
\n\n<b>3. Decentralized:</b>
\nA major pro of virtualcurrencies is that they are mainly decentralized. Many virtualcurrencies are controlled by the developers using it and those who have a significant amount of the coin or by a corporation to develop it before it’s released into the market. The decentralization helps keep the currency monopoly free and in restraint, so nobody organization can determine the flow and so the worth of the coin, which, in turn, will keep it stable and secure, unlike fiat currencies which are controlled by the Government.
\n\n<b>4. Cost-effective mode of transaction:</b>
\nOne of the most uses of virtualcurrencies is to send money across borders. With the help of virtualcurrency, the transaction fees paid by a user are reduced to a negligible or zero amount. It does so by eliminating the need for third parties, like VISA or PayPal, to verify a transaction. It removes the requirement to pay any extra transaction fees.
\n\n<b>5. Currency exchanges finish smoothly:</b>
\nVirtualcurrency can be bought using many currencies rather like the US dollar, European euro, British unit of measurement, the Indian rupee, or Japanese yen. Varied virtualcurrency wallets and exchanges help convert one currency into another by trading in virtualcurrency, across different wallets, and by paying minimal transaction fees.
\n\n<b>6. Secure and private:</b>
\nPrivacy and security have always been concerns for virtualcurrencies. The blockchain ledger relies on different mathematical puzzles, which are hard to decode. It makes virtualcurrency safer than ordinary electronic transactions. Bitcoincurrencies are for better security and privacy, and they use pseudonyms that are unconnected to any user account or stored data that might be linked to a profile.
\n\n<b>7. Easy transfer of funds:</b>
\nBitcoincurrencies have always kept themselves as an optimal solution for transactions. Transactions, whether international or domestic in virtualcurrencies, are lightning-fast. It will be because the verification requires little time to process as there are only some barriers to cross.

</string>
    <string name="str16">The year 2021 saw a lot of milestones with respect to growth and adoption of virtualcurrencies in India. Global inflows in digital coins so far this year added up to a robust $9.5 billion with two more weeks to go for 2021. In 2020, total virtual inflows were $6.7 billion.\n\nThe most popular digital coin, Bitcoin, is tipped to end the year almost double its December 2020 levels. Bitcoin has retreated 32% to $47,043 levels since hitting an all-time high of $69,000 on November 10\n\nSeveral factors which led to the largest virtual by market value retreating from its all-time high include China crackdown on virtual, tax provision in US infrastructure legislation, India’s proposed legislation to ban private coins led to panic selling. Other top digital currencies include Ether, which is also the second-largest by market value and currently trading around $3,753.07.</string>
    <string name="str15">Now as virtual transforms into an increasingly mainstream industry, even the ostensibly legitimate actors — start-up founders, engineers and investors — insist on anonymity. A growing number of virtual entrepreneurs, many of whom control hundreds of millions of dollars in investor funds, conduct business via mysterious internet avatars scrubbed of identifying information. Some venture capital firms are backing founders without ever learning their real names.\n\nBut the near collapse of Wonderland is forcing a reckoning over whether this culture of anonymity undermines accountability and enables fraud. Last month, BuzzFeed News set off a fresh round of debate by identifying two of the pseudonymous founders of Bored Ape Yacht Club, a $2.5 billion collection of nonfungible tokens, the unique digital collectibles known as NFTs.</string>
    <string name="str14">Private blockchains like Ripple and Hyperledger have the advantage of speed because a smaller set of users means less time to reach a consensus to validate a transaction. Private blockchains can process thousands of transactions every second and are easily scalable.\n\nA private blockchain has a centralised network that quickens the transaction process. Having a centralised network also raises the issue of trust, which is resolved in a public blockchain. A transaction’s validity cannot be verified on private networks and relies on the authorised nodes’ credibility. Additionally, fewer nodes make the network more susceptible to malicious attacks. The anonymity of public blockchains has also made it a major go-to transaction method for nefarious activities in the darknet, as it is difficult to trace the parties involved.</string>
    <string name="str13">The original blockchain was designed to operate without a central authority (i.e. with no bank or regulator controlling who transacts), but transactions still have to be authenticated.
\n\nThis is done using virtualgraphic keys, a string of data (like a password) that identifies a user and gives access to their “account” or “wallet” of value on the system.
\n\nEach user has their own private key and a public key that everyone can see. Using them both creates a secure digital identity to authenticate the user via digital signatures and to ‘unlock’ the transaction they want to perform.
\n\nOnce the transaction is agreed between the users, it needs to be approved, or authorised, before it is added to a block in the chain.
\n\nFor a public blockchain, the decision to add a transaction to the chain is made by consensus. This means that the majority of “nodes” (or computers in the network) must agree that the transaction is valid. The people who own the computers in the network are incentivised to verify transactions through rewards. This process is known as ‘proof of work’.
    </string>
    <string name="str12">If you invested your money in the stock market in March 2020, you have done quite well. The widely followed S and P 500 has effectively doubled in value since hitting its pandemic low.\n\nBut if you bought virtualcurrencies, you are probably dancing in the streets. That is because the aggregate value of digital currencies has skyrocketed more than 1,200% to $1.87 trillion since the March 2020 bottom.\n\nWhile most investors tend to gravitate to virtual big two — Bitcoin (BTC -12.34%) and Ethereum (ETH -21.28%) — because they make up more than 60% of the aforementioned $1.87 trillion market cap of digital currencies, there exists a world of innovation well beyond these two blue chip coins.</string>
    <string name="str11"><b>To engage in financial transactions without exclusively relying on banks or governments.</b>\n\nThe very first virtualcurrency created is known as Bitcoin. Bitcoin was created as a way for people to engage in financial transactions without exclusively relying on banks or governments. It is a digital currency that allows you the freedom to make transactions at any time and with anyone, anywhere around the world with limited restrictions.\n\nBitcoin was created out of the turmoil of the 2008 Great Recession as distrust of banks and their role in the financial system grew. An individual or a group of people going by the name Satoshi Nakamoto issued a white paper to address the centralized control of money and the trust required in handling citizens cash.</string>


    <string name="str10">Many investors consider bitcoin to be the original virtualcurrency. Founded in 2009 by a programmer (or, possibly, a group of programmers) under the pseudonym Satoshi Nakamoto, bitcoin ushered in a new age of blockchain technology and decentralized digital currencies.\n\nIn 1983, the American virtualgrapher David Chaum conceived an anonymous virtualgraphic electronic money called ecash.Later, in 1995, he implemented it through Digicash, an early form of virtualgraphic electronic payments. Digicash required user software in order to withdraw notes from a bank and designate specific encrypted keys before it can be sent to a recipient. This allowed the digital currency to be untraceable by the issuing bank, the government, or any third party.In 1998, Wei Dai published a description of b-money, characterized as an anonymous, distributed electronic cash system.[20] Shortly thereafter, Nick Szabo described bit gold.Like Bitcoin and other virtualcurrencies that would follow it, bit gold (not to be confused with the later gold-based exchange, BitGold) was described as an electronic currency system which required users to complete a proof of work function with solutions being virtualgraphically put together and published.</string>
    <string name="str9"> A virtualcurrency is a digital or virtual currency that is secured by virtualgraphy, which makes it nearly impossible to counterfeit or double-spend. Many virtualcurrencies are decentralised networks based on blockchain technology—a distributed ledger enforced by a disparate network of computers. A defining feature of virtualcurrencies is that they are generally not issued by any central authority, rendering them theoretically immune to government interference or manipulation. \n\nBitcoincurrencies are digital or virtual currencies underpinned by virtualgraphic systems. They enable secure online payments without the use of third-party intermediaries. "Bitcoin" refers to the various encryption algorithms and virtualgraphic techniques that safeguard these entries, such as elliptical curve encryption, public-private key pairs, and hashing functions.\nBitcoincurrencies can be mined or purchased from virtualcurrency exchanges. Not all ecommerce sites allow purchases using virtualcurrencies. In fact, virtualcurrencies, even popular ones like Bitcoin, are hardly used for retail transactions. However, the skyrocketing value of virtualcurrencies has made them popular as trading instruments. To a limited extent, they are also used for cross-border transfers.</string>
    <string name="str8"><b>1. The first commercial bitcoin transaction was for pizza</b>
\nOn May 22, 2010, a man in Florida paid 10,000 bitcoin for two pizzas. This is generally recognized as the first commercial bitcoin transaction.
At the time, 10,000 bitcoin was worth about $40, making one bitcoin worth a little less than half a cent. Today, if you had that much in bitcoin, it would be worth more than $350 million.
\n\n<b>2. There are more than 9,500 virtualcurrencies in existence</b>
\nAs of March 2022, there were more than 9,500 virtualcurrencies in existence. While you can’t buy them all on an exchange, they are out there, some of them requiring their own wallets.
There are so many coins and tokens available because it is relatively easy to create a virtualcurrency and put it out there. But, as of March 2022, the top 20 coins account for about 87% of the virtualcurrency market.
\n\n<b>3. The total amount of bitcoins is limited</b>
\nWhen the protocol for Bitcoin was set up, the limit was set at 21 million. As a result, at some point, no more bitcoins can be mined.
When you help complete transactions on the Bitcoin blockchain, you are said to be mining, and you can receive a reward in bitcoins. The reward halves every 210,000 blocks, which has worked out to about every four years. As of March 2022, some estimates put the total number of circulating Bitcoin at almost 19 million. This leaves a few million Bitcoin yet unreleased, which is part of why mining remains a popular activity.
\n\n<b>4. One man wants to excavate a landfill to get his digital wallet back</b>
\nIn 2013, James Howells, who lives in Wales, threw out a hard drive with 7,500 bitcoins on it. When he realized how much the value of Bitcoin had shot up in recent years, he went looking for the drive. Now, he’s trying to get his local city council to allow him to excavate the landfill in an attempt to find the drive. He’s claiming to offer a portion of the proceeds if the city allows him to look through the trash.
\n\n<b>5. Some cryptos, like Ethereum, have more uses than as a coin</b>
\nSome virtualcurrencies have uses beyond just being a coin. The Ethereum blockchain can be used for more than just processing payments and sending currency.
While you can use ether, the native coin, for transactions, the underlying technology is not just about a medium of exchange. Ethereum is also used to execute smart contracts and can be used for supply chain management. Other virtualcurrencies even create their coins on the Ethereum network.
\n\n<b>6. Ethereum fees are referred to as gas</b>
\nWhen using the Ethereum blockchain to complete transactions, you are required to pay for gas. On the Ethereum network, gas represents the computational effort used to complete the transaction.
Using the network for apps or transactions, even if it is converting another coin to ether, means you need to pay for gas. Depending on the transaction and traffic on the blockchain, gas fees can feel quite high in some cases.
\n\n<b>7. BitcoinKitties is one of the first blockchain games</b>
\nOne of the first blockchain games, BitcoinKitties offers a way to breed one-of-a-kind digital cats. BitcoinKitties are not a currency — instead, they are part of the non-fungible token (NFT) world.
Each kitty is unique and cannot be replicated; therefore, they have a unique value, similar to artwork. By the way, BitcoinKitties are built on the Ethereum blockchain.
\n\n<b>8. The most expensive BitcoinKitty sold for 600 ETH</b>
\nBack in 2018, someone paid 600 ETH for a BitcoinKitty Dragon. At the time of the sale, 600 ETH was worth about $170,000. Today, though, with the price of one ether at more than $2,500, that 600 ETH would be the equivalent of more than $1.5 million. That is one expensive digital cat!
\n\n<b>9. NFTs are not currencies</b>
\nEven though they are growing in popularity and are considered digital assets, NFTs are not virtualcurrencies. They are tokens that are not used as a medium of exchange. And NFTs cannot be divided or replicated.
Today, NFTs are seeing popularity as alternative investments similar to artwork or collectibles. In fact, that is how some people see them — digital collectibles and artwork that could potentially grow in value. There are even NFTs, like those offered by NBA TopShot, that operate similarly to digital sports trading cards.
\n\n<b>10. Dogecoin started as a joke</b>
\nOne of the hottest virtualcurrencies in recent months is Dogecoin. However, the token started out as a joke.
The idea was that there were so many coins out there, just being introduced. So the creators of Dogecoin invented the token around the image of the surprised-looking Shiba Inu dog. This was a popular meme in 2013 when Dogecoin was introduced.
While there is serious money in Dogecoin right now, its price remains volatile.
\n\n<b>11. The creator (or creators) of Bitcoin remain anonymous</b>
\nBitcoin is widely credited as being created by Satoshi Nakamoto. However, the paper that talked about the protocol was released through a virtualgraphy mailing list and the actual author remains anonymous.
There is a lot of speculation around the identity of Satoshi Nakamoto, but no one knows whether it’s one person or a group of people.
\n\n<b>12. Elon Musk has a lot of pull when it comes to virtualcurrency prices</b>
\nOne person has contributed to huge swings in virtualcurrency prices in recent months — Elon Musk. When he tweets or talks about virtualcurrencies, the market listens. Or at least his devoted followers listen.
Musk has impacted the price of Bitcoin and Dogecoin, and the virtualcurrency market as a whole, just from making pronouncements about what coins Tesla will accept for car purchases and making comments on Saturday Night Live.
Despite Musk’s antics, many investors still find themselves researching how to invest in Tesla itself.
\n\n<b>13. Some countries ban virtualcurrencies</b>
\nNot every country allows the use of virtualcurrencies. Some countries, like Turkey, do not allow virtualcurrency payments, while others, like Nigeria, ban virtualcurrency exchanges. One of the most significant recent bans, though, is China ban on financial institutions from providing services related to virtual transactions.
It is practically impossible to actually ban the use of virtualcurrencies, even though countries can regulate access to service providers and shut down exchanges. But with one of the world largest economies coming out against virtualcurrencies, it is hard to say how things will progress later.
\n\n<b>4. China used to account for about 65% of virtualcurrency mining</b>
\nIn May 2021, China proposed consequences for telecommunications companies and others that use their equipment for mining. By August 2021, China had been so effective at cracking down, that the country share of the global hash rate had fallen to zero.
Researchers believe some covert mining is still occurring, masked by the use of virtual private networks (VPN). Yet China swift action and the resulting rapid halt in Chinese virtualcurrency mining operations underscores the vulnerability of the virtualcurrency market to policy decisions by large nations.
\n\n<b>15. Virtualcurrency prices are extremely volatile</b>
\nVirtualcurrency prices are punctuated by wide swings in price. It is not uncommon for a coin to lose 30% to 50% of its value overnight — and then log huge gains a few days later. It is a new asset class, and people are trying to figure out how to value various coins.
Additionally, all of the celebrity surrounding cryptos mean there’s a lot of trendiness associated with them. As a result, if something falls out of favor, it could lose value quickly, and you could be left with losses you cannot recover.
\n\n<b>16. You still have to pay taxes on your virtual gains</b>
\nIf you are investing in virtualcurrencies and seeing gains, you will have to pay capital gains taxes. Depending on how you manage your virtual and how you got it, you might have to pay taxes based on long-term or short-term investment gains or as income.
For example, when I received one bitcoin for an article in 2011, that would have been considered income. Today, though, if I sell the Ethereum I bought in 2016-2017, my profits would be long-term capital gains. I experimented with Dogecoin back in April, and that resulted in short-term capital gains. All of that is taxed.</string>

    <string name="str7">Virtualcurrency has become a global phenomenon in recent years, although much is still to be learned about this evolving technology. There are many concerns and worries swirling around the technology and its capacity to disrupt traditional financial systems.\n\nJoseph A. Grundfest, professor at the Stanford Law School, recently sat down to discuss how virtualcurrency is currently being used, where mistakes have been made, and what the future holds for this technology. As a former commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission and expert on financial systems, Professor Grundfest is in a unique position to comment on the future of virtualcurrency.</string>
    <string name="str6"><b>1. Transaction speed</b>
\nIf you want to send someone money in the United States, there are few ways to move money or assets from one account to another faster than you can with virtualcurrency. Most transactions at U.S. financial institutions settle in three to five days. A wire transfer usually takes at least 24 hours. Stock trades settle in three days.
But one of the advantages of virtualcurrency transactions is that they can be completed in a matter of minutes. Once the block with your transaction in it is confirmed by the network, it is fully settled and the funds are available to use.
\n\n<b>2. Transaction costs</b>
\nThe cost of transacting in virtualcurrency is relatively low compared to other financial services. For example, it is not uncommon for a domestic wire transfer to cost $25 or $30. Sending money internationally can be even more expensive.
Virtualcurrency transactions are usually less expensive. However, you should note that demand on the blockchain can increase transaction costs. Even so, median transaction fees remain lower than wire transfer fees even on the most congested blockchains.
\n\n<b>3. Accessibility</b>
\nAnyone can use virtualcurrency. All you need is a computer or smartphone and an internet connection. The process of setting up a virtualcurrency wallet is extremely fast compared to opening an account at a traditional financial institution. There is no ID verification. There is no background or credit check.
Virtualcurrency offers a way for the unbanked to access financial services without having to go through a centralized authority. There are many reasons a person may be unable or unwilling to get a traditional bank account. Using virtualcurrency can allow people who do not use traditional banking services to easily make online transactions or send money to loved ones.
\n\n<b>4. Security</b>
\nUnless someone gains access to the private key for your virtual wallet, they cannot sign transactions or access your funds. However, if you lose your private key, there is also no way to recover your funds.
Furthermore, transactions are secured by the nature of the blockchain system and the distributed network of computers verifying transactions. As more computing power is added to the network, it becomes even more secure.
Any attack on the network and attempt to modify the blockchain would require enough computing power to confirm multiple blocks before the rest of the network can verify the ledger accuracy. For popular blockchains such as Bitcoin (CRYPTO:BTC) or Ethereum (CRYPTO:ETH), that kind of attack is prohibitively expensive.
Instances of hacked virtualcurrency accounts are usually tied to poor security at a centralized exchange. If you keep your virtual assets in your own wallet, it is far more secure.
\n\n<b>5. Privacy</b>
\nSince you do not have to register for an account at a financial institution to transact with virtaulcurrency, you can maintain a level of privacy. Transactions are pseudonymous, which means you have an identifier on the blockchain — your wallet address — but it does not include any specific information about you.
This level of privacy can be desirable in many cases (both innocent and illicit). That said, if someone connects a wallet address with an identity, all of the transaction data is public. There are several ways to further mask transactions, as well as several coins that are privacy-focused to enhance the private nature of virtualcurrency.\n</string>

    <string name="str5">Investing in virtual assets is risky but also <b>potentially extremely profitable.</b> Virtualcurrency is a good investment if you want to gain direct exposure to the demand for digital currency. A safer but potentially less lucrative alternative is buying the stocks of companies with exposure to virtualcurrency.Owning some virtualcurrency can increase your portfolios diversification since virtualcurrencies such as Bitcoin have historically shown few price correlations with the U.S. stock market. If you believe that virtualcurrency usage will become increasingly widespread over time, then it probably makes sense for you to buy some virtual directly as part of a diversified portfolio. For every virtualcurrency that you invest in, be sure to have an investment thesis as to why that currency will stand the test of time. If you do your research and learn as much as possible about how to invest in virtualcurrency, you should be able to manage the investment risk as part of your overall portfolio.</string>
    <string name="str4"><b>Virtualcurrency is stored in digital wallets.</b> Virtualcurrency received its name because it uses encryption to verify transactions. This means advanced coding is involved in storing and transmitting virtualcurrency data between wallets and to public ledgers. \n\nOnce you have purchased virtualcurrency, you need to store it safely to protect it from hacks or theft. Usually, virtualcurrency is stored in virtual wallets, which are physical devices or online software used to store the private keys to your virtualcurrencies securely. Some exchanges provide wallet services, making it easy for you to store directly through the platform. However, not all exchanges or brokers automatically provide wallet services for you. \n\n●	<b>Hot wallet storage: </b>"hot wallets" refer to virtual storage that uses online software to protect the private keys to your assets. \n●	<b>Cold wallet storage:</b> Unlike hot wallets, cold wallets (also known as hardware wallets) rely on offline electronic devices to securely store your private keys.</string>
    <string name="str3">Once you’ve learned the lingo, accepted the risk, and met your other financial priorities, the next step to virtual investing is actually buying in. There are thousands of different virtualcurrencies, but experts say you should take a hard pass on most of them. \n\nBitcoin values fluctuate by the hour, and this can be especially true for lesser-known coins. Even more established virtualcurrencies like Ethereum and Bitcoin experience their share of volatility, but at least have a greater record of increasing in value over time. \n\nThe process for buying Ethereum — or any other altcoin —  is the same as the process for buying Bitcoin, but we will use Bitcoin as an example throughout as it’s the most valuable and most widely-held virtual on the market right now.</string>
    <string name="str2">Virtualcurrency works a lot like PayPal or a credit card, except you exchange digital assets for goods and services instead of US dollars. To make a transaction with virtualcurrency, you must exchange currency with a peer using a digital wallet known as a virtualcurrency wallet. A virtualcurrency wallet is software that allows you to transfer funds from one account to another. To complete a transaction, you need access to a password, known as a private key. The private key is much like a bank account. You can own multiple keys and own all the funds sent to those keys. Transactions are recorded on a public ledger, which shows the transaction totals without revealing the identities of the parties involved. \n\nVirtualcurrency mining is the process required to verify transactions. It involves a massive amount of computing power and complicated algorithms, but those who are successful at solving problems through mining can earn reward coins, tokens, or transaction fees.</string>
    <string name="str1">On October 31, 2008, Satoshi Nakamoto published the white paper called Bitcoin – A Peer to Peer Electronic Cash System, describing the functionality of the Bitcoin blockchain network. Satoshi formally began work on the bitcoin project on August 18th, 2008, when they purchased Bitcoin.org. While it is not the subject of this article, it is worth noting that Bitcoin, and all virtualcurrencies, would not be possible without blockchain technology. \n\nThe history of Bitcoin was now underway.Satoshi Nakamoto mined the first block of the Bitcoin network on January 3, 2009. Satoshi embedded the headline of the newspaper The Times on the first block in order to permanently refer to the economic preconditions that lead to the technology of Bitcoin. This first block of 50 Bitcoins is now referred to as the Genesis Block. Bitcoin had almost no value for the first few months of their existence. Six months after they started trading in April 2010, the value of one Bitcoin was less than 14 cents. In May the pizza was bought, and by early November it surged to 36 cents before settling in at around 29 cents.</string>
</resources>